podomatic.com 2019-09-30

# Podomatic | Best Free Podcasts

Thank you for visiting Podomatic, the largest independent podcasting community. Podomatic is committed to honoring the privacy of Our members and visitors. This privacy policy, part of Our overall Terms of service (<https://www.podomatic.com/about/tos>) (“Terms of Service”), covers personal information shared through Podomatic. 

This privacy policy applies to [https://www.podomatic.com](https://www.podomatic.com/) (the “Website”), owned and operated by Podomatic, Inc. (“Podomatic”, “We”, “Our”, “Us”). This privacy policy describes how We collect and use the personal information you provide on the Website. It also describes the choices available to you regarding Our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

Podomatic, Inc. complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Podomatic, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield, and to view our certification page, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over Podomatic's compliance with the Privacy Shield. 

In compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles, Podomatic, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Podomatic, Inc. at: [legal@podomatic.com](mailto:legal@podomatic.com) or Podomatic, Inc. Att: Legal Department, 10 Cleveland Street, San Francisco, CA 94103 USA. 

Podomatic, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/> for more information and to file a complaint 

Finally, as a last resort and in limited situations, EU individuals may invoke last resort binding arbitration before a Privacy Shield Panel. 

Podomatic takes your privacy seriously. We will not sell, lease, or exchange your personal data to, or otherwise share your personal data with, third-parties in ways other than described in this Privacy Policy. By using Podomatic, including services available at the Podomatic.com domains, you are using a service provided by Podomatic, Inc. (collectively, the “Service”) and you agree to be bound by the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. Some capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy and not otherwise defined may be defined in the Terms of Service. This Privacy Policy only addresses activities from Our servers. 

By accessing our Service, you accept our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, and you consent to our collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. In addition, by using our Service, or services across partnered and unaffiliated sites, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. Each time you visit our website, or use the Service, and any time you voluntarily provide us with information, you agree that you are consenting to our collection, use and disclosure of the information that you provide, and you are consenting to receive emails or otherwise be contacted, as described in this Privacy Policy. Whether or not you register or create any kind of account with us, this Privacy Policy applies to all users of the website and the Service. 

By using the Service, you represent that you are at least 18 years of age. 

* Information Collection & Use

#### Registration

The Podomatic Service requires a login in order to provide you with a personalized account. During Our account registration process, We will collect an email address, your first and last name, and a password from you. You must provide all of this information in order to obtain an account. After completing Our registration form, you will receive a welcome email describing your new Podomatic account, and how to access that account. You may, at your option, also store your social media credentials as part of your account with Our Service. 

#### Communications with Podomatic

We use third party service providers to assist Us in managing and administering communications and emails sent to Us through the Website and through some Podomatic managed sites. Any personal information disclosed through such communications will be governed by such third party vendors’ privacy policies. 

#### Account Subscriptions

If you choose to continue service with Podomatic via a paid account, Podomatic will collect the following personal information from you: full billing address, credit card number, credit card expiration date, and zip code, and keep this information on file in Our secure server in order to process your recurring invoices. You may, at your option, also provide your company name, phone number. This information is used to verify credit card authenticity, and process payments as per your applicable service agreement. Upon discontinuation of Podomatic service, your credit card information will be destroyed on Our billing system. If We are unable to process your subscription for a given month, this information, along with your account information, may be used to contact you. 

#### Third Party Payment Processors

Podomatic uses third party payment processors to assist it in processing your personally identifiable payment information securely. Such third party processors’ use of your personal information is governed by their respective privacy policies which may or may not contain privacy protections as protective as this privacy policy. Payments are currently processed and managed using the third party vendors below. We will inform you which payment processors are used when processing your payments. 

<https://www.cybersource.com/privacy/> <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>

#### Server Logs

When accessing web pages on the Website, Podomatic may log your IP address, access URL, time of access, geographic location, browser type, and referral URL in order to provide Us with internal information regarding site traffic statistics. This information may also be used to identify users who are using the service for spam or other activity that is deemed in conflict with Our Terms of Service. Otherwise, this information is used in the aggregate, and is never linked back to any personal information. 

#### Comments and User Content Posted to the Website

If you post any Comments or User Content on the Website, you should be aware that any personal information you choose to provide there may be read, collected, or used by other users of the Website, as well as other third parties. We cannot guarantee that other users have not made copies of and/or will not use such information outside of the Website. We are not responsible for information you choose to post in this forum. 

#### Social Media

The Website provides users the opportunity to interact and post content through various social media sites. Your interactions with such tools, and any information you provide in connection with these interactions are publicly viewable outside of the Website domain. Each social media site has its own privacy policies, that may be more or less protective than this Policy. If you do not wish for this information to be disclosed, then you should not use these tools. We are not responsible for information you choose to post with such tools. 

Our site also includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button, and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on Our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on Our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on Our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

* Uses of Information

Podomatic collects the aforementioned personal information in order to provide you with a service that allows you to create, browse , search and listen to podcasts. Various features in Our Podcast management system will, at your discretion, display your name, or adjust the date and time of events based on your locale. 

Podomatic also uses information collected through its Service to send out notifications regarding service related issues (such as maintenance periods, billing problems, account expirations, and other items that may impact service). We also may use and disclose your information to Our third party service providers in order to send you messages regarding new services or other products from Podomatic. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to Us. 

Information collected through Our service logs is used only to identify potential cases of abuse and establish statistical information regarding Website traffic. This statistical information is not otherwise aggregated in such a way that would identify any particular user of the system. 

Podomatic, Inc. is the sole owner of information collected on [https://www.podomatic.com](https://www.podomatic.com/). Your information is never shared, leased or given to any third parties in ways other than disclosed in this Privacy Policy. 

* Information Security

We store all user information in secure databases protected via a variety of industry-standard access controls. Secure passwords, SSL encryption, disk-based encryption, firewalls, and other measures are in place to help Us protect your data. However, no company, including Podomatic, can fully eliminate security risks associated with the transmission of personal information through online transactions, and you do so at your own risk. 

* Access to Personally Identifiable Information

#### Changing Information

All information that Podomatic stores related to your account, including any subscription billing information, is accessible through your Podomatic account. You may use this interface to correct, update or delete your information at any time, and We encourage you to keep this information up to date so that your customer service requests and billing processes operate efficiently. 

#### Removing Information

To remove your personal information from Our system, submit your account for deactivation. Your personal information will be removed immediately, though your actual login name will remain reserved on Our system until re-collection. If you wish to only remove your billing subscription information, cancel your paid account. If you registered thorough Paypal, cancel your subscription via Paypal. 

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with Our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce Our agreements. 

* Communications from Podomatic, Inc.

#### Service-related Announcements

We will send you service-related announcements on occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if Our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, We might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. 

#### Other Messages

With your permission, We may also send you messages from time to time about new features or services that We will offer to Our users. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking on the link at the bottom of Our communications to you, or by changing your preferences in your profile as further described below. 

#### Customer Service

Upon issuing a customer support request to Podomatic, We may use your information and email address to contact you regarding your inquiry. 

#### Opt-Out

Only non-promotional service announcements, as described above, will be issued without prior authorization. If you do not want to receive promotional announcements from Podomatic about new products or services, you opt-out at any time by clicking on the link at the bottom of Our communications to you, or by changing your preferences in your account. We will not send you further promotional announcements. 

* Information Sharing and Disclosure

#### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We share aggregated demographic information about Our user base with Our marketing partners. This information does not identify individual users. This information contains statistics related to traffic and the geographic location of Our customers. We also may share aggregated user information with third parties who help Us to analyze Our user base to improve the Service. 

Other than as described herein, We do not link aggregate user data with personal information. 

#### Personally Identifiable Information

Podomatic employs third-party service providers to perform functions on Our behalf. Examples include credit card processing, email service providers, analyzing data, providing customer service. These service providers have access to personal information needed to perform such functions on Our behalf and authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to Us. 

In the event of a business transfer or sale by Podomatic, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the commitments made in any Podomatic pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless, of course, you indicate otherwise). 

We may release account and other personal information when We believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply Our Terms of Service; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Podomatic, Our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

#### Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials to enforce and comply with the law. We may be required to disclose and may disclose Your personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national securities or law enforcement requirements. 

Other than as set out above, you will receive notice when information about you might go to third parties, and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share the information. Podomatic is liable for appropriate onward transfers of personal data to third parties. 

* Your rights and choices regarding our use and disclosure of your Personal Data

#### Choices relating to your Personal Data

You may decline to provide Personal Data when it is requested by Podomatic, but certain Services or all of the Services may be unavailable to you. 

#### Opting out of receiving electronic communications

If you no longer wish to receive marketing-related emails from us, you may opt-out via the unsubscribe link included in such emails. We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails from Podomatic, we may still send you important administrative messages that are required to provide you with our Services. 

#### How to see or change your Personal Data

If you would like to review, correct, or update your Personal Data that you have previously disclosed to Podomatic, you may do so by signing in to your Podomatic account or by contacting us at [legal@podomatic.com](mailto:legal@podomatic.com). 

#### Your data protection rights

Depending on your location and subject to applicable law, you may have the following rights with regard to the Personal Data we control about you: 

  * The right to request confirmation of whether We processes Personal Data relating to you, and if so, to request a copy of that Personal Data; 
  * The right to request that We rectify or update your Personal Data that is inaccurate, incomplete or outdated; 
  * The right to request that We erase your Personal Data in certain circumstances provided by law; 
  * The right to request that we export to another company, where technically feasible, your Personal Data that we hold in order to provide Services to you. 

Where the processing of your Personal Data is based on your previously given consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You may also have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data on grounds relating to your particular situation. 

#### Exercising your data protection rights

In order to exercise your data protection rights, please Contact Podomatic as described in the Contact Us section below. Podomatic takes each request seriously and will comply with your request to the extent required by applicable law. We will not be able to respond to a request if we no longer hold your Personal Data. If you feel that you have not received a satisfactory response from us, you may consult with the data protection authority in your country. 

For your protection, we may need to verify your identity before responding to your request, such as verifying that the email address from which you send the request matches your email address that we have on file. If we no longer need to process Personal Data about you in order to provide our Services or our Sites, we will not maintain, acquire or process additional information in order to identify you for the purpose of responding to your request. 

* Log Files

As is true of most websites, We gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer websites, to track users' movements around websites and to gather demographic information about Our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personal information. 

* Cookies

We and Our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts to analyze trends, administer the Website, tracking users’ movements around the Website, and to gather demographic information about Our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. 

We use cookies for authentication, tracking user sessions, preferences, and movements around the website, anonymous and aggregated marketing analytics, performance analytics, retargeting, and tracking aggregate trends. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use Our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of Our website may be limited. 

* Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with third parties to either display advertising on Our Website or to manage Our advertising on other sites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) (or if located in the European Union click [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

* Canada and California Visitors

#### Canadian Visitors to the Site

Canadian citizens, except under circumstances defined by law, are entitled to access their own personal information collected by Podomatic by writing to: Podomatic, Inc., 10 Cleveland Street, San Francisco, CA 94103. Podomatic may ask you to pay an administrative fee for accessing or copying your personal information, but will inform you of the anticipated charges and confirm that you want Us to proceed before processing your request. If you believe that the personal information about you that We have collected is incomplete or inaccurate, We will correct the information upon verification of the omission or error, and the identity of the person requesting the change. If you require additional information about Our personal information management, or wish to access, correct or have Us investigate any matters in relation to your personal information, please contact Us. 

#### California Residents

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users who are California residents and who have provided with "personal information" (as that term is defined in Section 1798.83) to request certain information about the disclosure of that information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident with questions regarding this, or how the Podomatic reviews and processes any request from you to amend your personal information, please contact Us through our customer support system or in writing to Podomatic, Inc., 10 Cleveland Street, San Francisco, CA 94103. 

#### Notice for Visitors to the Website Outside of the United States

You should be aware that the United States and other countries have not harmonized their privacy regulations. Because Podomatic and its servers are located in the United States, Podomatic has written its Privacy Policy to satisfy United States regulations. By using Podomatic.com, you agree to the level of privacy protection set out in Our Privacy Policy. 

* Bulletin Boards / Chat Rooms / Member Websites / Testimonials

If you use a bulletin board or chat room on the Website, or on any Podomatic member website, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from Our blog or community forum, contact Us at [legal@podomatic.com](mailto:legal@podomatic.com). In some cases, We may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case We will let you know if We are unable to do so and why. 

Certain information, such as your name and IP address, is logged by Our system when posting messages, and is made available to the owner of the website you are posting on. These items may be displayed to readers of the site you are posting on, depending on the settings of that particular site. If you would not like to have these details disclosed, refrain from posting messages to any Podomatic bulletin board or chat room. 

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on Our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent We may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact Us at [legal@podomatic.com](mailto:legal@podomatic.com). 

* Links to Other Sites

This Website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Podomatic, Inc. Please be aware that We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave Our site and to read the privacy of each and every website that collects personal information. This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by this Website. 

* Changes in this Privacy Policy

If We decide to change Our privacy policy, We will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the homepage, and other places We deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information We collect, how We use it, and under what circumstances, if any, We disclose it. We will not materially change Our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If We make material changes to this Privacy Policy, We will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice within your Podomatic account prior to the change becoming effective. 

* Children Under 13

Podomatic is not directed to children under 13 years of age and We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If We become aware that a child under 13 has provided Us with personal information, We will delete such information from Our files. 

* Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding Our privacy policy, please contact Us by using Our customer support system. 

Podomatic is located at:  
Podomatic, Inc.  
10 Cleveland Street  
San Francisco, CA, 94103, USA  

All correspondence should be sent to:  
Podomatic, Inc.  
ATTN: Legal Department  
Re: Privacy Concern  
10 Cleveland Street  
San Francisco, CA, 94103
